GDP growth is not a good indicator of how well a country is performing, and should not be the primary goal of governments.
GDP增长并不是衡量一个国家表现如何的好指标，也不应成为政府的首要目标。
Unlimited growth is not sustainable and economic thinking is moving toward the idea that we should aim for sustainability in our economic models.
无限的增长是不可持续的，经济学思想正在转向这样一种观点：我们应当在经济模式中追求可持续性。
But while a sustainable economy is vital to our future, it is a means to an end, not an end in itself.
但是，可持续的经济虽然对我们的未来至关重要，却是达到目的的手段，而不是目的本身。
The idea that governments should focus on happiness has its critics.
认为政府应当关注幸福的观点不乏批评者。
There are concerns about how happiness can be measured.
有人对如何衡量幸福心存担忧。
Is happiness not a fleeting and subjective psychological state?
幸福难道不是一种转瞬即逝的主观心理状态吗？
Don’t different people experience different levels of happiness?
不同的人难道不会感受到不同程度的幸福吗？
Even on the broadest interpretation of “happiness” as prosperity or “life satisfaction”, people want different things.
即便对“幸福”作最宽泛的解读，将其理解为生活兴旺美满或“生活满意度”，人们想要的东西也各不相同。
Of course, governments cannot impose life satisfaction on citizens.
当然，政府无法把生活满意度强加给公民。
But our happiness relies on collaborative efforts as a society.
但我们的幸福有赖于整个社会的协作努力。
A government’s obligation lies in creating conditions that promote prosperity.
政府的义务在于创造有助于人们生活兴旺美满的条件。
And there is good reason to suppose that such conditions exist, are globally applicable, and are discoverable through research.
而且，有充分的理由认为，这样的条件是存在的，在全球都适用，并且可以通过研究发现。
In a recently published article, philosopher Julian Baggini suggests we should focus on “real wealth” for citizens, which does not depend on GDP growth.
在最近发表的一篇文章中，哲学家朱利安·巴吉尼提出，我们应该关注公民的“真正的财富”，这种财富并不依赖于GDP增长。
Access is key: people do not need to own, but rather access, things that enable them to live well.
关键在于使用权：人们并不需要拥有那些能让自己过上好生活的东西，而是需要能够使用它们。
Technological advances and changes in social behavior enable us to make more efficient use of the assets that we already have.
技术进步和社会行为的变化，让我们能够更高效地利用已有的资产。
And focusing on access to the resources people need to live better lives could help reduce inequality.
而且，关注人们能否使用过上更好生活所需的资源，或许有助于减少不平等。
As far as it goes, this has much in common with proposals tabled by “happiness” advocates.
单就其涉及的范围而言，这一主张与“幸福”倡导者提出的建议有很多共同之处。
But it sets the bar far too low for what governments can and should be doing for their citizens.
但就政府能够而且应当为公民做的事情而言，它把标准定得实在太低了。
For example, it’s not clear how a “real wealth” economy would remedy the epidemic of mental ill-health that plagues our society.
例如，以“真正的财富”为本的经济要如何治理困扰我们社会的心理疾病流行问题，这一点并不清楚。
In Western countries, at least, poor mental health is more detrimental to wellbeing than poverty.
至少在西方国家，心理健康状况不佳对福祉的危害比贫穷更大。
Over and above a vastly improved provision of therapeutic mental healthcare, there are preventative measures for improving mental health that governments could and should adopt.
除了要大幅改进治疗性心理健康服务的供给，政府还可以而且应当采取一些改善心理健康的预防措施。
The WHO recommends establishing institutions that facilitate community participation, and educational programs and interventions that provide skills for promoting mental wellbeing.
世界卫生组织建议设立促进社区参与的机构，并推行能让人们掌握增进心理福祉技能的教育项目和干预措施。
It says a lot, however, that the WHO feels the need to appeal to the economic benefits of improving mental health to persuade governments that the cost of taking proposed measures is justified.
然而，很能说明问题的是，世界卫生组织觉得有必要诉诸改善心理健康带来的经济效益，以说服各国政府相信，采取所提议措施的成本是合理的。
As long as the economy is their priority, governments need go no further than ensuring citizens’ continued productivity.
只要政府以经济为优先事项，就只需确保公民保持生产力，而不必更进一步。
To demand that governments set the “happiness” of citizens as their highest priority is to demand that they view citizens as ends in themselves.
要求政府把公民的“幸福”作为最高优先事项，就是要求政府把公民视为目的本身。